Allan Araujo

Android Developer

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/allan8araujo/

Github: github.com/allan8araujo Email: allan8araujo@gmail.com 20 | February | 1997 Pernambuco, Brasil +55 8198892-9070

summary

I am passionate about mobile development and building products that users love. I have three years of experience and specialize in Kotlin and Java. I have implemented and provided support for solutions for NTT DATA clients, including a popular app on the Play Store called "Itaú Empresas" with over five million downloads, collaborating in the transfer, cash flow, and sales squads.

I care about creating products that make users happy, and I ensure this through testing, teamwork, and code quality.

work experience

NTT Data

Android Developer, Apr 2022 - Currently

- Collaborate with a team of developers to develop and maintain a complex banking app for Itau, the largest bank in Latin America, with 5 million users.
- On "<u>Itaú Empresas</u>" collaborated on cash transfer and sales squad.
- In another Itaú project collaborated on cash flow squad.
- Utilize expertise in Android development to design and implement new features, troubleshoot and resolve technical issues, ensuring client needs are met.
- Utilize Android SDK expertise to design and build important features, ensuring client needs and expectations are met.
- · Learn best development practices and provide support in a bank app development.

Unique Sistemas

Mobile Developer, Jul 2021 - Apr 2022

- Maintain and develop mobile applications, including the user interface and the local server.
- · Publish applications on the Google Play Store.
- · Prototype screens using Figma.

São Sebastião Municipal School

Math Teacher, Feb 2020 - Jul 2021

- Provide pedagogical support, assisting in conducting Mathematics classes and monitoring students with learning difficulties.
- Participate in pedagogical meetings and continue professional development.

Montadora Guararapes

Administrative Assistant, Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

- Provide administrative support in the admin sector, with responsibilities in financial management using Excel and Word.
- · Assist in employee management.

programming languages

Kotlin Java Python Delphi

academic education

Major in Mathematics

Federal Rural University from Pernambuco (UFRPE)

I participated in the organizing team as a monitor

of Pymat 2021 and Pymat 2022

(Jul/2017 - Present) | Expected graduation: 2024

languages

Português: native Inglês: B2 - intermediate Spanish: A1 - basic

certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF) Jun 25, 2023

AWS Certified Developer Associate (currently studding)

technologies and frameworks

Android SDK, **Jetpack Libraries**, **Jetpack Compose**Android Unit Testing: **Espresso**, **JUnit** and **Robolectric**

Android Data Persistence: SQL3 and Room Concurrency: Android Kotlin Coroutines

Dependency Injection: Koin Cloud Services: AWS, Firebase

Analytics: Google Analytics, and Firebase Analytics

Cross-platform development: Flutter (Dart) and Delphi (firemonkey)

Versioning and communication: Git, Github, Gilab and Jira

UI/UX Design: Figma and Photoshop

courses

Kotlin NTT Data Android Developer (Digital Innovation One)

Conclusion: Feb/2022 | 106 hours

Topics: Git, Scrum, Kotlin, MVVM, SQLite, and

Android Studio

Android Application Development using Kotlin (Udemy)

Conclusion: Jul/2022 | 33 hours Topics: Kotlin, MVVM, and Retrofit

Android Developer Beginner (Udemy)

Conclusion: Jul/2022 | 7.5 hours

Topics: Java, Android Studio, Activity & Lifecycle, and Layouts (linear, relative, and constraint)

Firebase Courses:

Save NoSQL Data to Firestore (Alura)

Conclusion: Dec/2022 | 8 hours

FirebaseAuthentication: Apps Integration

· Conclusion: Nov/2022 | 10 hours

Advance Android Apps with Jetpack Compose: Create Screens and Manage States (Alura)

Creating an Android App

· Conclusion: Jan/2023 | 10 hours

Topics: Using LazyLayout and States

Conclusion: Feb/2023 | 10 hours

Topics: Form and State Management

Conclusion: Feb/2023 | 10 hours
Topics: Keeping States with ViewModel

· Conclusion: Mar/2023 | 12 hours

Data Science with Python (DataCamp)

Currently studying | 88 hours

Topics: Python, NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, and

Matplotlib

Data Manipulation (SQL, SAS, and Excel)

Machine Learning (Scikit-Learn)

HTML Web Developer Bootcamp (Digital Innovation One)

Conclusion: May/2021 | 26 hours

Topics: HTML, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, and

JavaScript

Advanced Development with Python, Flask, and RestAPI (Digital Innovation One)

Conclusion: Apr/2021 | 5 hours

Topics: Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy

AWS Courses:

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

Conclusion: Jun/2023 | 6 hours

Introduction to Amazon Web Services, Compute in the Cloud, Global Infrastructure and Reliability, Networking, Storage and Databases, Security, Monitoring and Analytics, Pricing and Support, Migration and Innovation, The Cloud Journey and AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Basics.